Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Animal Liberation Front Archived Website, Oct 10, 2007-Dec 29, 2011; Animal Liberation Front
  The Animal Liberation Front (ALF) consists of small autonomous groups of people all over the world who carry out direct action against animal abuse in the form of rescuing animals and causing financial loss to animal exploiters, usually through the damage and destruction of property.
  Direct action.; Animal rights
- Animal Liberation Front Archived Website, Aug 16, 2010- ongoing; Animal Liberation Front
  The Animal Liberation Front (ALF) carries out non-violent direct action against animal abuse in the form of rescuing animals and causing financial loss to animal exploiters, usually through the damage and destruction of property. ALF's goal is to save as many animals as possible and directly disrupt the practice of animal abuse to eventually end all animal suffering by forcing animal abuse companies (agribusiness, laboratories, etc.) out of business. Because ALF actions may be against the law, activists work anonymously, either in small groups or individually, and do not have any centralized organization or coordination. The ALF also advocates veganism or vegetarianism.
  Site crawls were discontinued and captures were deaccessioned Fall 2015.
  Animal rights; Direct action.; Animal rights activists.
- Asia Pacific Forum Archived Website, Sep 21, 2014-ongoing; Asia Pacific Forum of National Human Rights Institutions
  Asian Pacific Forum was founded in 1998, when Samori Marksman, program director of WBAI, and Sybil Wong, former business director of WBAI, brought together a group of journalists and activists to organize a weekly program focused on New York's Asian communities. In 2006, APF began podcasting and making its weekly broadcasts available as downloads on the web, allowing the show to reach a broader audience both nationally and globally. The website contains programs on activism, immigration, civil and human rights, politics, and other topics. The website also has a listing of songs on the station, book recommendations, news, and event listings.
- Asian CineVision Archived Website, Mar 27, 2014-ongoing; Asian CineVision (Organization)
  Asian CineVision (ACV) is a non-profit media arts organization that develops, promotes and preserves media made by or about peoples of Asian descent. Asian CineVision was founded by grassroots media activists in New York's Chinatown in 1976 to raise social and cultural awareness of the Asian American experience, both in the Asian American community and among the general public. CineVue Online is ACV's media arts journal established in 1986. The website contains their media arts journal, information on their Asian American International Film Festival, news listings, event listings, and press releases.
  Asian Americans in television broadcasting.; Asian American motion picture producers and directors.; Asian Americans.; Asian American International Film Festival
- Asian American Arts Centre Archived Website, Mar 25, 2014-ongoing; Asian American Arts Centre
  The Asian American Arts Centre, founded in 1974 as Asian American Dance Theatre, is one of the older community arts organizations in New York City Chinatown. The current name, Asian American Arts Centre, was adopted in 1987 to encompass both the dance company (Asian American Dance Theatre) and the visual arts program, Asian Arts Institute, initiated in 1984. In 2007, the Asian American Art Centre created a new archive, the AAAC Artist Archive. 150 artists who exemplified the major issues that compose the subject of Asian American art were selected and their materials processed for long-term archival preservation. The website contains a blog with details on past and current exhibitions, the digital archive of art, and information related to community organizing in Chinatown.
  Asian American art.; Community and school |z New York (State) |z New York.; Art |x Political aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.; Asian Americans -- New York (State) -- New York.
- Asian American Legal Defense Fund Archived Website, Sep 29, 2007-ongoing; Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund
  Founded in 1974, the Asian American Legal Defense and Education Fund (AALDEF) is a national organization that protects and promotes the civil rights of Asian Americans. By combining litigation, advocacy, education, and organizing, AALDEF works with Asian American communities across the country to secure human rights for all.
- Association for Neighborhood and Housing Development Archived Website, Mar 18, 2012 - ongoing; Association for Neighborhood and Housing Development
  The Association for Neighborhood and Housing Development (ANHD), founded in 1974, is a membership organization of New York City nonprofit neighborhood housing groups engaged in community development and organizing throughout the city. ANHD's mission is to protect neighborhoods and provide affordable housing for all New Yorkers. ANHD provides training, technical assistance and advocacy for and on behalf of member organizations. The website contains member organization listings, resources, and training materials.
- Autonomedia Archived Website, Sep 21, 2007- ongoing; Autonomedia.
  Founded in 1984, Autonomedia is a North American publisher of radical theoretical works, especially in the anarchist tradition. Autonomedia publishes books on topics such as anarchism, Marxist works, cyberfeminism, drug literature, turn of the 21st century queer individualist anarchist novels, and other works. They are known for publishing the "Autonomedia Calendar of Jubilee Saints," in which every day of the calendar recalls a deceased person of some significance to progressive movements or thought. They also maintain the Interactivist Info Exchange, an online forum for discourse and debate on themes relevant to the books that they publish.
  Alternative mass media |z United States.; Art -- Political aspects -- United States; Artists |x Political activity |z United States.; Small presses -- United States.
- Black Left Unity Network Archived Website, May 7, 2012-Aug 6, 2013; Black Left Unity Network
  The Black Left Unity Network is a network in solidarity with the Black Liberation movement, which opposes racist and anti-immigrant laws. The website publicizes information about strikes and other actions.
  Radicalism; African Americans.
- Blackout Arts Collective Archived Website, Oct 3, 2007-May 19, 2014; Blackout Arts Collective
  Blackout Arts Collective (BAC), founded 1997 in New York, is a grassroots coalition of artists, activists and educators working to empower communities of color through the arts.
  Art -- Political aspects -- United States; Artists |x Political activity |z United States.
- Black Radical Congress Archived Website, Aug 15, 2009 - Sep 10, 2013; Black Radical Congress
  The Black Radical Congress (BRC), founded in 1998 in Chicago, is a radical African American activist coalition of organizations and individuals focused on advocating for broad progressive social justice, racial equality and economic justice goals within the United States. The BRC holds conferences and other programs. The website only gives information on the BRC's history and biographical information on notable individuals relating to the BRC.
  African American radicals.; Black nationalism.
- Brecht Forum Archived Website, Aug 15, 2009- ongoing; Brecht Forum (New York, N.Y.)
  The Brecht Forum, originally located at 451 West Street in Manhattan, now at 388 Atlantic Avenue in Brooklyn, is a Marxist cultural and educational center. The Brecht Forum was founded in 1975 as The New York Marxist School. In 1984, the founding collective incorporated as The Brecht Forum with The New York Marxist School as the Forum's core project. In addition to the New York Marxist School, it also offers other programs, language classes, and arts and cultural events. The website contains information on their curriculum and classes, as well as economic news analysis.
  Communism and education.; New York Marxist School
- Bureau Public Secrets Archived Website, Mar 9, 2010- ongoing; Knabb, Ken
  A situationist website, largely consisting of situationist writings in several languages, apparently edited by Ken Knabb.
  Internationale situationniste.
- Campaign for Peace and Democracy Archived Website, Jul 8, 2009- ongoing; Campaign for Peace and Democracy
  The Campaign for Peace and Democracy, founded in 1982, works to advance a progressive and non-militaristic U.S. foreign policy and is opposition to current U.S. foreign policy. Orginally, the campaign engaged Western peace activists in the defense of the rights of democratic dissidents in the Soviet Union and Eastern Europe, and enlisted East-bloc human rights activists against anti-democratic U.S. policies in countries like Nicaragua and Chile. The majority of the Campaign's work has been its efforts to work with dissidents and social justice movements worldwide, and to forge alliances between them and progressive movements in the United States. The website contains petitions, endorsements, action alerts, news analysis, and endorsements.
  Peace movements -- United States.; International cooperation.; Social justice.; United States -- Foreign relations.; Human rights.
- Campaign to Stop Killer Coke Archived Website, Dec 2, 2010- ongoing; Campaign to Stop Killer Coke
  The Campaign to Stop Killer Coke is a worldwide movement based on the efforts of thousands of volunteers. Ray Rogers is the director of the Campaign to Stop Killer Coke. His organization, Corporate Campaign, Inc., created the Campaign to Stop Killer Coke to hold The Coca-Cola Company, its bottlers and subsidiaries accountable and to end the gruesome cycle of violence including the systematic intimidation, kidnapping, torture and murder of union leaders and members of their families in efforts to crush their unions, particularly in Colombia and Guatemala.
  Human rights |z Colombia.; Social responsibility of business.; Employee rights |z Columbia.; Employee rights |z Guatemala; Human rights -- Guatemala.; Coca-Cola Company
- Camp Delta Standard Operating Procedure Archived Website, Nov 21, 2007-Jul 12, 2009; WikiLeaks (Organization)
  Contains the United States Dept. of Defense Joint Task Force Guantanamo (JTF-GTMO) standard operating procedures (SOP) for Camp Delta (Guantanamo Bay prison), 2003 and related documents. This is the primary document for the operation of Guantanamo bay, including the securing and treatment of detainees. The document is extensive and includes, in addition to text various forms, identity cards and even Muslim burial instructions. It is signed by Major General Miller, who Donald Rumsfeld later sent to Abu Ghraib to "Gitmoize it". The document is also the subject of an ongoing legal action between the ACLU, which has been trying to obtain it, and the Department of Defense, which has withheld it in full. Wikileaks is a multi-jurisdictional organization to protect internal dissidents, whistleblowers, journalists and bloggers who face legal or other threats related to publishing. Wikileaks provides a forum for the entire global community to relentlessly examine any document for its credibility, plausibility, veracity and validity.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp
- Camp Kinderland Archived Website, Apr 1, 2012- ongoing; Camp "Kinderland" (Hopewell Junction, N.Y.)
  Camp Kinderland was founded on Sylvan Lake in Hopewell Junction, NY in 1923 by members of the Workmen's Circle who worked in the organization's New York City schools. The camp's founders sought to create a summer youth camp that would not only provide a recreational escape for the children of working people from the tenements of New York City, but also one whose culture would encourage and foster a commitment to socially progressive activism and the embracing of a rich Jewish secular tradition. The website contains news and event listings, camper and parent resources, and information about renting their facilities.
  Jewish children -- United States.; Camps |x Massachusetts.
- Campus Activism Archived Website, Feb 20, 2012- ongoing; Campus Activism
  CampusActivism.org, established in 2002, operates as a networking tool and database for student activists. The website works with activists to share contact information, event information, ideas, and resources. The website contains tools to add and browse email lists, campaign notices, issues, events, contacts, groups, and resources.
  Student movements -- United States.
- Center for Constitutional Rights Cases: Illegal Detentions and Guantanamo Archived Website, September 2009-October 2017; Center for Constitutional Rights (New York, N.Y.)
  Contains websites of cases taken by the Center for Constitutional Rights in relation to illegal detention and the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp
  Torture |z United States.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Moral and ethical aspects -- United States.; Human rights |z United States.
- Center for Constitutional Rights Archived Website, Feb 7, 2007 - ongoing; Center for Constitutional Rights (New York, N.Y.)
  The Center for Constitutional Rights (CCR), founded in 1966 by attorneys who represented civil rights movements in the South, is dedicated to advancing and protecting the rights guaranteed by the United States Constitution and the Universal Declaration of Human Rights. CCR is a non-profit legal and educational organization committed to the use of law as a force for social change. Some issues CCR works on is illegal detention and Guantanamo, surveillance and attacks on dissent, criminal justice and mass incarcerations, corporate human rights abuse, government abuse of power, racial and gender justice, and international law and accountability. The website lists news and current cases. Note that the CCR's records are at the Tamiment Library.
  Civil rights -- United States.; Human rights.
- Center for Constitutional Rights Active Cases Archived Website, June 2015-ongoing
  List and accompanying documentation related to active cases of the Center for Constitutional Rights. Issues focused on by CCR include abusive immigration practices, corporate human rights abuses, criminalizing dissent, discriminatory policing, drone killings, government surveillance, Guantanamo, LGBTQI persecution, mass incarceration, Muslim profiling, Palestinian solidarity, racial injustice, sexual & gender-based violence, and torture, war crimes, & militarism.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  This website was added as a replacement for http://ccrjustice.org/cases-issue, which became defunct in 2014 and redirected to https://ccrjustice.org/home/what-we-do/active-cases in 2015. The website was added to the Guantanamo Bay Detention Camp & War Crimes (U.S.) Web Archive in 2018. The accession number associated with this website is 2019.090.
  Appraisal
  Crawl was limited to host URL in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
- Central New York Reds Archived Website, Apr 28, 2013- ongoing; Central New York Reds
  Central New York Reds is the website for the Socialist Party of Central New York. The organization holds regular Socialist forums to discuss and debate important topics and to include radical perspective, organize protests, and other activities. The website contains event listings, information about their platform, resources, and a blog.
  Socialism -- New York (State).
- Code Pink Archived Website, Nov 11, 2009- ongoing; Codepink: Women for Peace
  CODEPINK is a women-initiated grassroots peace and social justice movement working to end the wars in Iraq and Afghanistan, stop new wars, and redirect resources into healthcare, education, green jobs and other life-affirming activities. CODEPINK rejects foreign policies based on domination and aggression, and instead calls for policies based on diplomacy, compassion and a commitment to international law. The website sponsors events and is made up of action alerts, a blog, and a media center.
  Iraq War, 2003-2011 -- Protest movements -- United States.; Women and peace -- United States.; Peace movements -- United States.
- Color Of Change Archived Website, Jul 7, 2011- ongoing; ColorOfChange.org
  ColorOfChange.org works to strengthen Black America's political voice, make government more responsive to the concerns to Black Americans and to bring about political and social change. ColorOfChange.org is comprised of Black Americans from every economic class, as well as those from all backgrounds who seek to help Black Americans be heard. Members are united to make sure all Americans are represented, served, and protected regardless of race or class.
  African Americans -- Politics and government -- 20th century.
- Combatant Status Review Tribunal (CSRT) and Administrative Review Board (ARB) Documents Archived Website, Jul 11, 2009- ongoing; United States. Department of Defense. Military Commissions. Combatant Status Review Tribunals
  Contains unclassified summaries of evidence for Combatant Status Review Tribunals held between July 2004 and July 2007. Included are summaries for High Value Detainees (HVD). Other documents and audio recordings of testimony for HVD can be found on the Detainee Affairs webpage of DefenseLint at: http://www.defenselink.mil/news/Combatant_Tribunals.html.
- Committee Against Anti-Asian Violence (CAAAV) Archived Website, Oct 25, 2011- ongoing; CAAAV (Organization)
  Committee Against Anti-Asian Violence (CAAAV) works to build grassroots community power across diverse poor and working class Asian immigrant and refugee communities in New York City. Through an organizing model constituted by five core elements- basebuilding, leadership development, campaigns, alliances, and organizational development- CAAAV organizes communities to fight for institutional change and participates in a broader movement towards racial, gender, and economic justice.
  Discrimination against Asian Americans.; Asian Americans.
- Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism Archived Website, Aug 13, 2009- ongoing; Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism
  The Committees on Correspondence was organized in 1992 after the 1991 Communist Party USA convention as a non-Leninist, democratic socialist organization to dispute the policies and leadership of CPUSA head, Gus Hall. The movement centered around veteran communist and former leading CP official, Gil Green (1906-1997). The Committees on Correspondence sought to reach out to others on the left outside the Party, and held conferences in 1992 and 1994 to formally establish the new organization. Around 2000, the Committee on Correspondence changed its name to the Committees of Correspondence for Democracy and Socialism. The website contains information on their conventions, publications, including their newsletter, the Mobilizer, by- laws, and other materials.
  Socialists -- United States.; Socialism -- United States.; Socialism
- Communist Party USA Archived Website, May 10, 2008- ongoing; Communist Party of the United States of America
  The Communist Party of the United States of America (CPUSA) is a Marxist-Leninist political organization that was founded in Chicago in 1919. The CPUSA played a pivotal role in many significant political and social movements of the 20th century. Its Party platform focused largely on working class issues such as fair wages and unemployment, civil rights for racial and ethnic minorities, civil liberties for politically persecuted communities, economic justice for the poor, the unemployed and for immigrants, and international peace efforts. The Party's work left an indelible mark in the arena of progressive politics and made it an influential force in the labor movement, particularly from the 1920s to the 1940s. Its varied political, social, and cultural initiatives attracted the support of a number of prominent artists, intellectuals, and activists, including Woody Guthrie, Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, W.E.B. Du Bois, and Angela Davis. Though the CPUSA's strength and size declined sharply following World War II and the advent of the Cold War and McCarthyism, it remains committed to socialism, peace, economic and social justice, and civil rights and liberties. Today, the CPUSA continues its struggle for socialism, peace, and social and economic justice, and publishes a newspaper, the People's Weekly World (http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw11834j9g), a monthly journal, Political Affairs (http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/sw1r49hs90), and through its Labor Commission, the online periodical Labor Upfront (captured here: http://webarchives.cdlib.org/site/spec:0000000z7). The website contains a blog, event listings, action alerts, and other writings.
  Communism -- United States.; Communists -- United States.
- Communist Party USA: Southern California Communist Party Archived Website, Aug 26, 2010-Jan 20, 2012; Communist Party of the United States of America. Southern California District
  This website contains the small, briefly extant (2008-2009) blog of the Southern California organization of the Communist Party USA.
  Communism -- California.
- Communities United for Police Reform Archived Website, Dec 10, 2014-ongoing; Communities United for Police Reform
  Communities United for Police Reform is a campaign to end discriminatory policing practices in New York, and includes dozens of community organizations. Communities United for Police Reform was a key supporter of the Community Safety Act, a groundbreaking reform to the New York Police Department that was signed into law in 2014. The website includes news, resources, and campaign summaries.
  Police brutality.; New York (N.Y.).
- Cooperative Village Archived Website, Mar 28, 2012 - ongoing; Cooperative Village
  Cooperative Village is a community of housing cooperatives on the Lower East Side of Manhattan sponsored, organized and built by the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America and International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, as well as the United Housing Foundation, a development organization set up by the unions in 1951. The Cooperative Village manages four smaller corporations, Hillman Housing Corporation, East River Housing Corporation, Seward Park Housing Corporation, and the Amalgamated Dwellings. The cooperatives followed strict Rochdale Principles, with one vote per member. The website contains information on cooperative services and the corporation.
- Cooper Square Committee Archived Website, Mar 10, 2012 - ongoing; Cooper Square Committee
  The Cooper Square Committee (CSC), is a housing association of the Lower East Side, which works with area residents to contribute to the preservation and development of affordable, environmentally-friendly housing and community/cultural spaces. They provide housing and social services, including tenant counseling and eviction prevention; community and tenant organizing; social services and referrals; and community development. The website contains news updates, tenant rights resources, and project information.
  Low-income housing.; Tenants' associations.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions.
- CorpWatch Archived Website, Sep 24, 2007 - ongoing; CorpWatch
  CorpWatch, launched in 1996, is a site that uses investigative research and journalism to monitor and expose corporate malfeasance and to advocate for corporate accountability and transparency. They work to foster global justice, independent media activism and democratic control over corporations and promote human, social, environmental, and workers rights. They publish investigative reports on their website and they are affiliated with Friends of the Earth International.
  Corporations |x Corrupt practices.; Social responsibility of business.